if if you recommend someone starting on
the testosterone cream um what's the
typical frequency you recommend you
start out once a day twice a day all the
pumps in the morning um what's your
typical startup protocol with the cream
if we've got toppy clicks and we can
dose it in increments of 0.25 mil um one
to two clicks twice a day um if someone
is particularly old or particularly
obese or in a particularly poor state of
health
and their Baseline testosterone levels
in the gutter sometimes I think it's
best to start with one click twice a day
to bring them from here to here and then
after 12 to 16 weeks if needed we can
take them from here to here I don't see
any reason why they have to go from here
to here especially if they are
predisposed to developing side effects
um if someone's symptomatic at a
relatively Higher free testosterone
level then going to one click twice a
day might only take them from here to
here so it depends on where their
Baseline is and how much we want to
increase it
um in Australia where we only have the
0.5 mil increment so it's like two
clicks at a time in those circumstances
I will just recommend people start with
one click in the morning and then sorry
one click one pump in the morning and
then if we have to increase the dose
after that then we add the second pump
in the evening but you know Keith Keith
says it very well you know the most
important benefit of uh well the most
important variable to focus on when
optimizing cream is stability and that's
best achieved by twice daily dosing I
think you can do cream once a day um but
I think it's always going to be more
beneficial to do it twice a day but if a
guy sleeps naked with his wife then and
that's an important part of their
intimacy then I think that that's a if
that's something that he doesn't want to
lose or something that he doesn't want
to interrupt I think that that's a very
reasonable thing to go with a once
morning application so transference via
intimacy is a real factor with this and
if that's something that's going to be
something new to adjust to or you know
it's a complicating Factor then it
absolutely can all be done once in the
morning but yeah one two clicks twice a
day depending on the individual where
the blood work is the Bine state of
health would be what I'd recommend
starting them
[Music]